Today I am going to be showing you how to make Gourmet French Fries cooked in duck fat.
So we are currently heating up the oil and at this point, you are going to want to be very very careful unless you rendered the duck fat yourself.
I bought this at the store and there appears to be a great deal of moisture in the actual fat.
So what is happening, you see all the bubbles on top right there.
That is the water coming out of the oil which means it was probably improperly stored at the store or it was allowed to partially thaw and then refrigerate.
I am going to let this go until I don't see any bubbles in there.
I do have it a little hotter than usual.
It's about 350 right now and I want to get it to 325.
So I am just going to turn the heat down a little bit and let it back off some and wait for these bubbles to come out.
But like I said be really really careful.
It has already popped on me twice; really really big.
Like 2 foot high oil explosions so just be really really careful and make sure you don't burn your house down and don't burn yourself.